If you take the time yourself to calculate the value function for this policy,
如果你花时间自己计算了该策略的值函数
you might notice that you don't need to start your calculations from scratch every time.
可能会发现 你不用每次都从头开始计算
In particular, you don't need to look at
尤其是 你不需要查看第一个状态
the first state then add up all the rewards along the way.
将之后的所有奖励相加
Then look at the second state,
然后查看第二个状态
add up all those rewards.
并将所有奖励相加
Then the third, add up all those and so on.
然后查看第三个状态 将所有奖励相加 等等
It turns out to be redundant effort.
这么做属于重复工作
Instead there's something much faster that you can do.
实际上有快了很多的方法
So, let's erase most of these values with the exception of the ones at the bottom.
我们删掉大多数的值 只留下最底下的值
And let's see how we might work backwards to recalculate those values.
然后看看如何往回重新计算这些值
And along the way we'll discover that the value function has a nice recursive property.
在此过程中 我们将发现值函数有一个递归特性
To see that, let's say we're trying
为此 假设我们尝试计算
to calculate the value of the state that I've highlighted here.
我突出显示的状态的值
And, that's just the sum reward that follows until we reach the terminal state.
即抵达最终状态之前的奖励之和
And in this case, the agent starts in the state,
在此示例中 智能体从该状态开始
then follows the policy,
遵守该策略
gets a reward of negative one,
获得奖励 -1
and lands at this next state with the value of two.
然后进入这个值为 2 的下个状态
And what's important to notice here is that this two already corresponds
这里要注意的是 这个 2 已经对应了
to the sum of all the rewards that follow all the way to the end.
一直到结束时的奖励之和
So, instead of recalculating that sum,
我们不用计算这个和
we could just use that value of two to get the value of
而是使用值 2 得出
the state as negative one plus two or one.
该状态是 -1 加上 2 即 1
For the same reason,
同样
the value of the next state is negative one plus one or zero,
下个状态的值是 -1 加上 1 即 0
then negative three plus zero or negative three and so on.
然后是 -3 加上 0 即 -3 等等
In this way, we see that we can express the value of any state
这样 我们可以看出任何状态的值为
as the sum of the immediate reward plus the value of the state that follows.
即时奖励加上下个状态的值
And what's important to note,
需要注意的是
is that for simplicity,
为了简便
I set the discount rate in this example to one but
我将此示例中的折扣率设成了 1
in general we want to have a framework that takes discounting into account.
但是通常都需要考虑折扣
So, we'll need to use the discounted value of the state that follows.
因此我们需要使用下个状态的折扣值
We can express this idea in terms of what's known as
我们可以将此概念表示为
the Bellman expectation equation where for
贝尔曼预期方程
a general MDP we have to calculate the expected value of the sum.
对于一般的 MDP 我们需要计算和的预期值
This is because, in general,
因为通常
with more complicated worlds,
对于更加复杂的环境
the immediate reward and next state cannot be known with certainty.
我们无法确定即时奖励和下个状态
This equation is very important and we'll use it extensively in future lessons.
这个方程式非常重要 我们将在后续课程中经常用到它
But for now, all that's important to remember is the main idea.
暂时只需记住大概含义
And that idea is,
也就是
we can express the value of any state in the MDP in terms
我们可以将 MDP 中任何状态的值表示为
of the immediate reward and the discounted value of the state that follows.
即时奖励和下个状态的折扣值